

## Eduardo Francisco Sánchez Ocampo

in eduardosanchez270698

EduardoSanchezO.github.io

+52 833 235 07 46

Eduardo.Sanchez@cinvestav.mx

#### Soft Skills.-

Problem-Solving Analytical

Self- motivated Creative

## Languages Skills. ——

Spanish Native

English Advanced Level

# **AI ENGINEER**

#### Profile. —

Specialist focused on the development of complex algorithms based on artificial intelligence, my main applications rely on perception and control of robots. Due to the exponential growth of the industry, I am an adaptive individual with the ability to solve problems and make new creative products.

#### Work Experience. -

CINVESTAV-IPN / Intel labs
Research Assistant

5/2021 - Present

4 years

- Implementation of perception algorithms for obstacle detection using YOLO.v7 architecture and OpenCV.
- Motion planning for a bipedal robot based on deep reinforcement learning using Python, ROS environment and PyTorch, reducing 70% of computing.

Grupo SAC 7/2019 - 3/2021 **Technical Support in PEMEX equipment** 

- Preventive and corrective maintenance of PEMEX stations.
- Monitoring of rectified voltage reading.

#### Education.—

CINVESTAV-IPN Unidad Guadalajara 7/2021 - 7/2023

#### Master of Science in Electrical Engineering

Thesis: Deep Reinforcement Learning for Bipedal Motion Planning in Autonomous Navigation.

Universidad Politécnica de Altamira 8/2016 - 1/2020

### **Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering**

Thesis: Particle Swarm Optimization for Adaptive Control in Chemical Process

## Technical Skills.

Open CV 4.8

Matlab 2022.a 9.7 PyTorch 4 years 1 year C/C++ Dev-C++ 5.0 4 years TensorFlow 2 1 year Python 2.7, 3 3 years **Computer Vision** 1 year **Bash Shell Script** 2 years Supervised Learning 3 years ROS 18.04, 20.04 Reinforcement Learning 2 years 1 year

1 year

Robotics